Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
I. Edward Kiev papers
circa 1860-circa 1980
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Kiev, I. Edward (Isaac Edward)
K0001
40 Linear Feet
Isaac Edward Kiev (1905-1975) was born in New York City to Nathan and Anna (Radin) Kiev. In 1924, Kiev entered the Jewish Institute of Religion [JIR], a new rabbinical seminary established just two years earlier by renowned Jewish leader and activist Stephen S. Wise. In 1925, Kiev began work as a page in the JIR library to help pay for school and soon he took on more responsibilities including cataloging the Hebrew manuscripts. Although Kiev did not complete his studies at the JIR, he continued to work at the library, becoming Chief Librarian in 1942, a position he held until his death in 1975. In addition to his fifty years of service at the Jewish Institute of Religion, which merged with Hebrew Union College in 1950, Kiev also served as chaplain at Sea-View Hospital, a tuberculosis sanitarium, from 1927-75. He later became a pulpit at Congregation Habonim in New York, where he served Associate Rabbi from 1966 until 1973.
Bib#
8588663
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The I. Edward Kiev collection was donated to Gelman Library by Dr. Ari and Phyllis Kiev and their children, Dr. Jonathan Kiev and Marshall Kiev in 1996.
Biographical Note
Isaac Edward Kiev (1905-1975) was born in New York City to Nathan and Anna (Radin) Kiev. In 1924, Kiev entered the Jewish Institute of Religion [JIR], a new rabbinical seminary established just two years earlier by renowned Jewish leader and activist Stephen S. Wise. In 1925, Kiev began work as a page in the JIR library to help pay for school and soon he took on more responsibilities including cataloging the Hebrew manuscripts. Although Kiev did not complete his studies at the JIR, he continued to work at the library, becoming Chief Librarian in 1942, a position he held until his death in 1975. In addition to his fifty years of service at the Jewish Institute of Religion, which merged with Hebrew Union College in 1950, Kiev also served as chaplain at Sea-View Hospital, a tuberculosis sanitarium, from 1927-75. He later became a pulpit at Congregation Habonim in New York, where he served Associate Rabbi from 1966 until 1973.
Kiev was involved in Jewish library and book organizations, particularly after World War Two. Kiev was on the Advisory Committee of Jewish Cultural Reconstruction, Inc., an organization that was responsible inventorying and redistributing Jewish books and artifacts the survived the Holocaust and from 1949-51 he served as secretary. Kiev was president of the Jewish Librarians Association, the predecessor of the current Association of Jewish Libraries, from 1951 to 1959. Kiev worked extensively with the Jewish Book Council, serving as treasurer from 1954 to 1958, secretary from 1958 to 1966. He was an associate editor its publication, the Jewish Book Annual, from 1952 to 1975 and throughout those years wrote the bibliography of American non-fiction books. Kiev was also an editor for Library Trends and Studies in Bibliography and Booklore, contributed to other publications such as the American Jewish Year Book and translated the Kafra Haggadah, published by Feldheim in 1949.
Additionally, Kiev helped support the proliferation of modern Hebrew. He served as chair of the Israel Matz fund, which aided destitute Hebrew writers, including their widows and children, established Hebrew libraries, and funded the publication of literature that promoted Jewish culture. Kiev was a trustee of the Nissan Touroff Foundation that supported Hebrew writers and he chaired the Book Section Committee of the National Federation of Temple Brotherhoods' Jewish Chautauqua Society, which helped place Jewish-interest books in college and university libraries
During his tenure at the JIR, the library's collection grew from under 10,000 volumes to more than 100,000. In 1957 he was awarded an honorary Doctor of Divinity degree from the Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion. His stature was such that he was listed in Who's Who in America (1974, 1976, 1978); Who's Who in the World (1964, 1976), and Who's Who in World Jewry (1972). In 1971, Ktav published a festschrift in honor of his sixty-fifth birthday entitled, Studies in Jewish bibliography, history, and literature in honor of I. Edward Kiev.
On December 20, 1930, Kiev married Mary B. Nover, who also worked at the JIR Library. Mary went on to become librarian at New York's Temple Emanu-El from 1949-64. The Kievs resided in Washington Heights and had two children, Ari and Aviva.
I. Edward Kiev died in New York City 1975. __I. Edward Kiev developed an extensive personal library of approximately 18,000 volumes, consisting primarily of books related to Judaic Studies.
Collection Scope and Content
The material listed in this guide is processed and available for use.
Collection Organization
Organized into 6 series: Personal and professional papers, Photographs, Music, Pamphlets, Graphic arts, and Artifacts.
New York (N.Y.); United States; Hebrew language; Hebrew literature; Hebrew essays; Songs, Hebrew; Jewish literature; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Jerusalem; Tel Aviv (Israel); Israel; Warsaw (Poland); Music; Jews; Judaism; Photographs; Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion; Jewish Book Council of America; Jewish Institute of Religion (New York, N.Y.); Kiev, I. Edward (Isaac Edward); Temple Emanu-El
- Personal and professional papers, 1925-1975; K0001 Series 1; 1.5 linear feet (Box 53, Box 50, Box 54, Box 52)
  - General correspondence, 1925 - 1945 (Box 50, Folder 1781)
  - General correspondence, 1952 - 1969 (Box 50, Folder 1782)
  - General correspondence, 1970 - 1976 (Box 50, Folder 1812)
  - Application and letter to the Jewish Institute of Religion, 1924 (Box 50, Folder 1813)
    General note
    This is the only folder related to Kiev's vital statistics. So also included is information about Kiev changing his birthday and his membership card to the Department of Hospitals.
  - Master Plan for Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 1814)
  - Against the "Unification Plan", 1951 - 1954 (Box 50, Folder 1815)
    Regarding the plan to merge the Jewish Institute of Religion in New York, N.Y. with Hebrew Union College in Cincinnati, OH.
  - Louis I. Newman, 1955 - 1974 (Box 50, Folder 1816)
  - Committee for Archives and Research Libraries in Jewish Studies, 1973 - 1974 (Box 50, Folder 1817)
  - Israel Matz Foundation, 1964 - 1974 (Box 50, Folder 1818)
    I. Edward Kiev was chairman of this foundation
  - Ordination certificate form letters, undated (Box 50, Folder 1819)
    Form letters are printed in Hebrew
  - Bulletins including articles with I. Edward Kiev, 1951 - 1957 (Box 50, Folder 1820)
    Articles that include Kiev contain photographs
  - Invitations and programs, 1943 - 1969 (Box 50, Folder 1821)
  - Marrige records and certificates, 1936 - 1971 (Box 50, Folder 1822)
    Includes a confirmation letter in Hebrew from Rabbi Kiev certifying that someone is Jewish and acceptable to marry.
  - Library reports, 1950 - 1975 (Box 50, Folder 1823)
  - Jewish Institute of Religion, 1920 - 1944 (Box 50, Folder 1824)
    Includes meeting minutes, and the Constitution and By-Laws for the Jewish Institute of Religion
  - Honorary Doctor of Divinity degree, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 1825)
    Congratulatory letters and other materials related to Kiev receiving an honorary Doctor of Divinity degree from Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion in 1957.
  - Festschrift correspondence and reviews, 1968 - 1973 (Box 52, Folder 1867)
  - Invitations and letters related to Kiev's Festschrift receptions, 1971 - 1972 (Box 52, Folder 1868)
    Includes letters in English and Hebrew
  - Sea View correspondence and programs, 1947 - 1957 (Box 52, Folder 1869)
  - Congregation Habonim correspondence, 1970 - 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1870)
  - Congregation Habonim programs and bulletins, 1970 - 1973 (Box 52, Folder 1871)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, circa 1950 - circa 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1872)
  - Mary Kiev, 1961 - 1965 (Box 52, Folder 1873)
    Also included is Mary Kiev's grammar book from Herzliah Academy.
  - Family correspondence and invitations, 1932 - 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1874)
  - Condolence letters, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1875)
  - Kiev Library Foundation, 1975 - 1977 (Box 52, Folder 1876)
  - Miscellaneous cards and letters, 1948 - 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1877)
    Also includes a certificate from Hadassah honoring Kiev's contributions to Israel.
  - Reprints of Kiev's writings, 1944 - 1961 (Box 53, Folder 1878)
  - Sermons, circa 1955 - circa 1969 (Box 53, Folder 1879)
    These sermons are drafts of those reprinted posthumously in "Actions, Not Words."
  - Sermons, circa 1955 - circa 1969 (Box 53, Folder 1880)
  - Sermons, circa 1945 - circa 1975 (Box 53, Folder 1881)
    These drafts were not included in "Actions, Not Words."
  - Actions, Not Words (copy), circa 1955 - circa 1969 (Box 53, Folder 1882)
  - Miscellaneous Kiev writings, circa 1945 - circa 1975 (Box 53, Folder 1883)
  - Ismar Elbogen, 1912 - circa 1943 (Box 54, Folder 1884)
    Folder contains a postcard and letters written in German and Hebrew to Ismar Elbogen
  - Unidentified writings, undated (Box 54, Folder 1885)
    One piece is dated 1795 and may be valuable.
  - Unidentified writings (non-English), undated (Box 54, Folder 1886)
    Foreign languages including Hebrew, and possibly Yiddish and Arabic. Some materials are quite old and are possibly rare manuscripts.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 54, Folder 1887)
    One letter is in German.
  - Miscellaneous postcards, undated (Box 54, Folder 1888)
    Postcards are in a variety of languages, including English, Hebrew, and one German from 1942 (war years).
- Photographs, circa 1870-circa 1970; K0001 Series 2; 0.5 linear feet (Box 44)
  - Two photographs, undated (Box 44, Folder 1421)
    Includes photocopy of one of the photographs, which depicts a dinner of the Jewish Librarians Association in honor of Rabbi Chaim Lieberman.
  - Six photographs, undated (Box 44, Folder 1422)
    Four photographs show Mary Kiev, one with I.E. Kiev at a dinner and another with Mrs. Jeannette Salo Baron (among other women). One shows I.E. Kiev with Sam Zeldner in Princeton, NJ in 1973.
    Various other photographs depict a man wearing a tallit and cutting challah, women posing with flowers, and men and women attending dinner events.
  - Photograph, undated (Box 44, Folder 1422.01)
    Mary Kiev at a dinner with Mrs. Jeannette Baron (Mrs. Salo Baron) and other women
  - undated (Box 44, Folder 1422.02)
  - Three photographs from the dedication of the I. Edward Kiev festschrift in Jerusalem, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 1423)
  - Two photographs, undated (Box 44, Folder 1424)
    The color photograph depicts I.E. Kiev and several residents from the Sea View Hospital and Home in Staten Island, NY, where he was the chaplain for a number of years. The black and white photograph depicts a large group of people standing on the steps of a building at Sea View.
  - Photograph of six people, including Victor Eppstein and Albert Einstein, undated (Box 44, Folder 1425)
    Photograph is signed, "To my dear friend Kiev, Victor Eppstein." Eppstein, who is shown standing to Einstein's right, was I.E. Kiev's classmate and best friend.
  - Two photographs of Stephen Samuel Wise, undated (Box 44, Folder 1426)
    One photo is inscribed by Wise and reads, "friend and comrade," possibly referring to Kiev. The photo is dated October 1943.
  - Two photographs of I. Edward Kiev, undated (Box 44, Folder 1427)
    One photograph is an original while the other is a copy.
  - Photographs and negatives of I. Edward Kiev, undated (Box 44, Folder 1428)
    Photograph and negatives relating to the portrait in the Kiev Room, a photographic image of the one used to create the portrait, a negative of the photograph, a negative of the portrait, and a single negative with three 35mm strips from the photo session of the original portrait photograph.
  - Photographs and negatives, undated (Box 44, Folder 1429)
    Four different photographs with corresponding negatives, and one with multiple copies: (1) one colored photograph with two enlarged black and white reprints and negative of I.E. Kiev; (2) the other is an 8 x 10, black and white photograph of Mary Kiev at Temple Emanu-El's Library and negative; (3) one photograph of I.E. Kiev (reprint) with large columns behind him, along with negative, and (4) one of I.E. Kiev and another man on the left with negative.
  - Six photographs of I. Edward Kiev, undated (Box 44, Folder 1430)
    All have at least one reprint (duplicate), various sizes, black and white. Also included is a note from Phyllis Kiev concerning the photographs.
  - Twenty-six photographs, undated (Box 44, Folder 1431)
    (1) Barney and Naomi Nover. Barney was Mary Nover's brother and Washington D.C. correspondent for The Denver Post. After Barney's death in the early seventies Naomi became a White House correspondent. (2) I.E. and Mary Kiev ca. 1950. (3) Tea garden party at St. John's Wood in London, England in July, 1959. Mary Kiev is shown on the right. (4) Color photo of Mary Kiev ca. 1960. (5) Color photo of Mary Kiev, 1962. (6) Mary Nover (Kiev) at age six. (7) World Union London, 1959. Shows Mary Kiev and Mr. and Mrs. John Tepfer. John Tepfer was a professor at the Jewish Institute of Religion. (8) 1953 Passover seder at the home of I.E. Kiev. Shows Mary Kiev, Aviva Kiev, I.E. Kiev, Ari Kiev in the front. In the back are Rose Perper, Jack Perper and Nessie Levine. (9) I.E. Kiev, Susan Tabor and Katherine Markush. Tabor and Markush were assistants at the library. (10) I.E. Kiev with Professor Slonimsky and students at the Jewish Institute of Religion in 1925. (11) I.E. Kiev at synagogue with patients of the Sea View Hospital and Home. (12-16) I.E. Kiev as chaplain with tuberculosis patients at the Sea View Hospital and Home. (17) I.E. Kiev officiating at his daughter, Aviva's wedding. (18) Wedding of Aviva Warsha (I.E. Kiev's daughter). I.E. Kiev is in upper left. Phyllis Kiev is in long gown (as matron of honor) holding Barney Nover's hand. (19) Honorary doctorate reception. I.E. Kiev is on the far right. Also in photo is Nelson Glueck, chancellor of HUC-JIR. (20) I.E. Kiev shown third from the right in the top row. Stephen S. Wise shown fifth from the right on the top row, 1936. (21) Eight people around a dinner table. (22) I.E. Kiev in the JIR library office. (23) I.E. Kiev on far left, standing with five other men at the Jewish Book Council of America in New York. (24) Photograph of man with cyrillic writing, ca. 1900. (25) Photograph of a young man and woman, taken in New York, ca. 1900. (26) Black and white photograph of a couple wearing glasses.
  - Seven photographs from Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, 1926 - 1974 (Box 44, Folder 1487)
    (1) Faculty members and student body at the Jewish Institute of Religion, 1926. I.E. Kiev is shown second from the left on the top row. Mary Nover is the last on the right of the third row from the bottom. Stephen S. Wise in in the center of the front row. Photograh taken at 40, East 68th Street, NYC. (2) Faculty members from the three campuses of HUC-JIR in Cincinnati, 1974. (3) Twenty men inluding I.E. Kiev, Chaim Tchernowitz, Alexander Kohut and Stephen S. Wise. (4) Honorary doctorate reception at HUC-JIR. (5) Twelve men including I.E. Kiev, Paul Steinberg, John Tepfer and Henry Slonimsky. (6) Portrait of Chaim Tchernowitch with Hebrew inscription to I.E. Kiev. (7) Thirteen men and one woman, including I.E. Kiev, Henry Slonimsky, Stephen S. Wise and John Tepfer.
  - Six personal photographs of the Kievs, 1943 - 1962 (Box 44, Folder 1488)
    Reprints which did not come with the original donation. Sent by Ed and Phyllis Feld in 2004.
    (1) Dinner party at the Feld's apartment in the Bronx. Shows Mary Kiev, Ari Kiev and Phyllis's mother, Sarah, 1943. (2) From left side, top row to bottom, Phyllis's mother, Sarah, Phyllis's sister, Roselyn, and Ari Kiev. From the right side, top row to bottom, I.E. Kiev, Mary Kiev and Aviva Kiev, 1940. (3) Ari, Mary and I.E. Kiev, 1948. (4) From left to right, I.E. Kiev, Mary Kiev, Ari Kiev and his wife, Phyllis Kiev. In front is Ralph Feld, at whose Bar Mitvah party the photograph was taken, April 1962. (5) Mary and I.E. Kiev. (6) I.E Kiev and Avigda, his son-in-law.
- Music, circa 1900-circa 1970; K0001 Series 3; 2.5 Linear Feet 5 LP storage boxes; 12 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of long play albums [LPs]. There are 123 albums dating from circa 1911 to circa 1977. The series is divided into six subseries by musical genre.
  - Liturgical and cantorial records, 1921-1976; Series 3, Subseries 1
    Arrangement
    Arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
    Scope and Contents
    This subseries contains seventy-two record albums of Jewish prayer services and sacred music of the synagogue. Some of the most frequently featured cantors in this subseries include well-known names from the Golden Age of Jewish cantorial performance (the period between the two World Wars), such as Sawel Kwartin, Josef Rosenblatt, Gershon Sirota, Berele Chagy, and Mordecai Hershman.
    - Binder of sheet music, undated; Series 3, Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 1)
    - Cantor Berele Chagy in the Synagogue by Berele Chagy, undated; Series 3, Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 2)
    - Cantor Berele Chagy Sweet Singer of Israel by Berele Chagy, 1963; Series 3, Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 3)
    - Side A: (Kum zu mir in Cheder'l) Side B: (Mai Ko Mashma Lon) by Berele Chagy, undated; Series 3, Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 4)
    - Musica Hebraica Volume 2: The Sabbath Service by Raanan Eller; Emil Adar, Esther Nadiv, Avraham Alkai, Gladys Hedaya, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 5)
    - Beloved of Days: Sabbath Z'mirot Songs and Grace after Meals by Emanuel Goldsmith, 1958; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 6)
    - The Seventh Day by Mordecai Hershman, 1961; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 7)
    - Side A: Al Chet (Judgement on the Day of Atonement) Side B: A Gesang fun'm Berditchever Rebbe (The Berditchever Rabbi's Song) by Mordechay Hershman, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 8)
    - Side A: Boruch Adonoi Bayom (Blessed Be the Lord) Side B: Brich Shmei (Blessed Be the Name) by Mordechay Hershman, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 9)
    - Side A: Boruch Adonoi Bayom (Blessed Be the Lord) Side B: Brich Shmei (Blessed Be the Name) by Mordechay Hershman, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 10)
    - Side A: K'shimcho (For According to Thy Name) Side B: Udom Jesoidoi Meofor (In Truth, Thou Art Their Creator) by Mordechay Hershman, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 11)
      Originally sleeve 12 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Side A: Leolom Yehei Odom-Teil 1 (Always be a Man-Part 1) Side B: Leolom Yehei Odom- Teil 2) (Always Be a Man-Part 2) by Mordechay Hershman, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 12)
      Originally sleeve 6 in record book with a silver "K."
    - Side A: Dance on, Dance on (Tantzt, Tantzt, Yiddelach) Side B: Wedding Dance (Chupeh-Tantz) by Jewish-Russian Orchestra, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 13)
    - Sabbath In The Synagogue by Shalom Katz, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 14)
    - Two Master Cantors by Shalom Katz; Moshe Ganchoff, 1964; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 15)
    - Festival Gems: L'dor Vodor Unipnei Chatoeinu, Sheiboneh Beis Hamikdosh, Akavyo Ben Mahalalel by Moshe Kusevitsky, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 16)
      Set of 3 records (6 sides).
    - Side A: Brach dodi (Hasten, Dear God, to Redeem Our Temple) Side B: Maarovis (Evening Prayer for Passover) by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 17)
    - Side A: Al ken N'kawe Side B: Adonoj Adonoj by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 18)
      Originally sleeve 3 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Side A: Halbein Chatuenu (Jom Kippur) (Turn Thou Our Sins) (Day of Atonement) Side B: Hanshamo Loch (Slichos) (The Soul is Thine) (Selichoth) by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 19)
    - Side A: Hineni heoni, I. Teil Side B: Hineni heoni, II. Teil by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 20)
      Originally sleeve 9 in record book with a silver "K."
    - Side A: Jehi Ruzon Side B: Jchadschehu by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 21)
      Originally sleeve 10 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Side A: Kidush L'scholosch R'golim Side B: Ah-Wass Olom by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 22)
      Originally sleeve 5 of record book with Hebrew notes
    - Side A: Ovinu Malkeinu Side B: Odom Yesodoi Me'ofor by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 23)
    - Side A: Rehenu Beonjenu Side B: Kol Adonoj by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 24)
      Originally sleeve 8 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Side A: Udom jesodo Meofor Side B: Kewakuras by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 25)
    - Side A: W'chol maaminim schehu Side B: Hazur tumim um poolo by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 26)
      Originally sleeve 6 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Side A: W'hakohanim Side B: Jaale Tachnuneinu by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 27)
      Originally sleeve 4 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Side A: W'seurew l'funechu asiruseinu Side B: Kol Nidrei by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 28)
    - Side A: Zur Jisroel Side B: J'Hal' Lu by Sawel Kwartin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 29)
      Originally sleeve 1 of record book with Hebrew notes.
    - Music for the Jewish Home by Benjamin Landsman; North Shore Congregation Israel Choir, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 30)
    - Sacred Music of the Synagogue by Abraham Levitt, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 31)
    - Cradle Song (Napravnik) by Marie Michailowa, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 32)
    - Jewish Holiday Dances and Songs by Darius Milhaud; Leonard Bernstein, Ernst Toch, Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Hans Eisler, David Diamond, Trude Rittman, Reuven Kosakoff, Stefan Wolpe, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Item 33)
    - Side A: Kol Nidrei Side B: A Plea to God by Jan Peerce, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 1)
    - Columbia record book by P. Pinchik, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 2)
    - Cantor Pinchik Sings by Pierre Pinchik, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 3)
    - L'maan Tzion by Seymour Rockoff (Eliyahu Shalom), 1976; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 4)
    - Hanukah: Songs and More Songs for Hanukah by Emanuel Rosenberg; Judith K. Eisenstein, 1954; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 5)
      45 EP
    - Side A: (Atto Yozarto) Side B: (Birchas Kohanim) by Rosenblatt, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 6)
    - Side A: Atto Yozarto Side B: Birchas Kohanim by Rosenblatt, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 7)
    - Side A: HAKAVYO BEN MAHALAEL (Hakavjo, Son of Mahalael) Side B: WEHU RACHUM (He Being Merciful) by Rosenblatt, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 8)
    - Side A: (El Mole Rachmim) Side B: (Kol. Nidre) by Josef Rosenblatt, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 9)
    - Side A: (Elegie) (Massenet) Side B: (Eili Eili) by Josef Rosenblatt, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36A, Item 10)